<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Meng Chen Ph.D</title>
    <link>https://elegant-bardeen-3db241.netlify.app/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Meng Chen Ph.D</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://elegant-bardeen-3db241.netlify.app/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Narrative Persuasion in Health Promotion</title>
      <link>https://elegant-bardeen-3db241.netlify.app/research/narrative_persuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elegant-bardeen-3db241.netlify.app/research/narrative_persuation/</guid>
      <description>In my earlier research, I examined the strategic use of narrative persuasion in health promotion and disease prevention. For example, my PhD dissertation examined the effects of several language and content features of. At the same time, it also identified a serial mediation relationship which distinguishes narratives from other ordinary persuasion effort. I recently started a project investigating the impact of the linguistic cues and rhetoric features of narratives in online social support solicitation built on my earlier research on narrative persuasion and online social support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Media and Health Management</title>
      <link>https://elegant-bardeen-3db241.netlify.app/research/new_media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elegant-bardeen-3db241.netlify.app/research/new_media/</guid>
      <description>This line of research investigates the role played by new media in people’s health management and communication. Some of my recent projects use natural language as a window glancing into breast cancer patients’ online social support solicitation and disease coping.
Publications Chen, M., &amp;amp; Zhao, L. (2020). Mapping breast cancer survivors’ psychosocial coping along disease trajectory: A language approach. Journal of Health Psychology 1, 1-14
Chen, M., Bell, R. A., &amp;amp; Barnett, G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Health Crisis Journalism</title>
      <link>https://elegant-bardeen-3db241.netlify.app/research/health_crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elegant-bardeen-3db241.netlify.app/research/health_crisis/</guid>
      <description>The outbreak of COVID-19 has confronted the world with considerable political, economic, and public health crises, igniting heated debate in various fields worldwide. This project conducts a massive scale examination of COVID-19 media coverage from different perspectives and investigates how the media coverage impacts the epidemiological situation.
Publications Chen, M., &amp;amp; Zhao, L. (In Progress). Linking media coverage of COVID-19 with incidence rate: A computational content analysis of COVID-19 news along cognition, affection, and behavior dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
